# Eduardo Moraes de Mello

São Paulo

Mobile: +55 11 967884596 - E-mail: <u>eedu.mello@gmail.com</u>

https://www.linkedin.com/in/eedumello/

# **PROFILE**

I have over 5 years of experience working as software engineer. Currently, I work as Blueshift's Big Data Engineer, being part of a team responsible for architecting, design, prototyping and implement architectures to tackle the Big Data and Data Science needs for the customers. Previously, I worked with different skills as a service desk analyst.

### **EXPERIENCE**

BlueShift Brasil Ltda 2014 – 2019

Big Data Engineer

Roles & responsibilities:

- Acting as project leader architecting, design, prototyping and development architectures to tackle the Big Data and Data Science needs for customers.
- Responsible for designing and implementing cloud big data solutions using Microsoft Azure Platform, Google Cloud and Oracle BDCS.
- Integrate Hadoop into ETL process, accelerating the extraction, transformation, and loading of massive structured and unstructured data running on Hortonworks, Cloudera and MapR platforms.
- Create data flow ingestion using Apache NIFI, Apache Flume, Apache Kafka and Microsoft Data Factory.
- Build data pipelines using BigQuery, Pub/Sub and DataFlow on Google Cloud Platform
- Responsible for developing Big Data analytics platform for processing customer viewing preferences data using Python, Spark, Hadoop, Hive.
- Create SQL queries to integrate data visualization tools on Oracle and Microsoft Azure SQL.
- Create Sqoop jobs to transfer data between databases and Apache Hadoop environment.
- Development of plugins for Apache Flume and Apache Camel.
- Optimization of SQL and HQL queries for ETL process.
- Create SQL queries to integrate data visualization tools on Oracle, Microsoft Azure SQL and Microsoft Azure DW databases.
- Experienced in all project phases using Waterfall and Agile Methodologies

IBM 2013 – 2014

Service Desk Analyst

Roles & responsibilities:

- Delivered service by greeting and serving customers in a timely and friendly manner.
- Responsible for setup and configure software at customer's machines

City Hall 2010 – 2011

Internship

- Responsible for maintaining a SQL Server database system using DDL (Data definition language), DCL (Data control language), TCL (Transaction control language) and DML (Data manipulation language).
- Coding Stored Procedures, Functions and Triggers for the SQL Server database.
- Responsible for setup and configure the software at customer's server.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Paulista University, São Paulo

2014 - 2018

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science - Developed an benchmark between frameworks for batch and streaming processing systems: Apache Spark and Apache Flink.

#### **STRENGTHS**

- Ability to handle multiple projects simultaneously.
- Good teamwork qualities with excellent communication and interpersonal skills.
- Skill Variety: Customer service, time management, change agent, communication, system applications, critical thinking, problem resolution, analytical thinking.

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English Proficient
- Portuguese Native

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Google Cloud Certified Professional Data Engineer Google
- Data Engineering, Big Data, and Machine Learning on GCP Coursera Course Certificates License E2T6AF8GMUDT
- Hortonworks Data Platform Certified Developer
  Hortonworks

# TRAINING AND CONFERENCES

- 2019 Kanbam KMP I
- 2018 BlueShift: ApacheCon Download
- 2017 Apache: Big Data Conference

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Big Data**: HDFS, Spark, Hive, Impala, Sqoop, Flume, Kafka, HBase, Accumulo, Oozie, Nifi, Zeppelin, StreamSets, Airflow.

Environments: Cloudera, HortonWorks, Mapr.

**Google Cloud**: Cloud Storage, BigQuery, DataPrep, Pub/Sub, DataFlow, BigTable. **Microsoft Azure**: Blob Storage, Data Factory, CosmosDB, SQL Data Warehouse.

Amazon AWS: S3, EC2, EMR.

**General**: Python, Java, R, Shell Scripting, Javascript, MongoDB, SQL Server, Docker, JMS, Maven, Git, Jira, Scrum, Kanbam.

# PREFERRED LOCATION

• Willing to relocate as needed.

#### **REFERENCES**

• Available upon request.